Inventory of the Papers of Monroe Leigh, 1941 - 2001
University of Virginia, Arthur J. Morris Law Library
- Legal Papers
  - State Department Advisor
    - ALI Restatement: Reporters Committee v. Vance - C - Legal Documents, 1977 - 1978 (Box-folder 38 - 4)
      Contains underlines, notations, check-marks, fax cover letters, documents include: US Court of Appeals for DC Circuit list of relevant case numbers & memorandum, Proceedings transcript, delivered opinion (2 copies), Plaintiiffs reply memorandum of points and authorities in support of thier motion for a preliminary injunction, memorandum of points and authorities in support of plaintiffs' motions for summary judgment and, alternatively, a preliminary injunction, Affidavit of William E. Leuchtenburg, Affidavit of Nat Hentoff, Affidavit of William Safire, Affidavit of Donald G. Herzberg, Memorandum of points and authorities in opposition to plaintiffs' motions for summary judgment and in support of defendant Henry A. Kissinger's cross-motion for summary judgment, Opposition to plaintiffs' motions for summary judgment, Cross-motion for summary judgment by defendant Henry A. Kissinger, Memorandum of points and authorities in opposition to plaintiffs' motion for a preliminary injunction, Second Affidavit of Henry A. Kissinger, Order, Certificate of Service, Affidavit of Monroe Leigh, Memorandum of points and authorities in opposition to plaintiffs' motion for summary judgment and in support of defendant Henry A. Kissinger's cross motion for summary judgment, Complaint
    - ALI Restatement: Correspondence re: terrorism, nicaragua, May, July, August, November 1984 (Box-folder 38 - 5)
      Correspondents include: Monroe Leigh, George H. Aldrich, President Ronald Reagan, Sen. Arlen Specter, Henry A. Kissinger, Pamela B. Gann, Erwin N. Griswold, Mark R. Joelson, Stephen S. Rosenfeld,
    - ALI Restatement: Correspondence re: Nicaragua Case, May - June 1985 (Box-folder 38 - 6)
      Correspondents include: Monroe Leigh, Malcolm R. Wilkey, William W. Bishop, Jr., memorandum for Mary Lee re: Suggested Paragraph for Chairman Moore's Letter, John R. Stevenson
    - ALI Restatement: Correspondence re: US - UK extradition agreements, November 1985 (Box-folder 38 - 7)
      Correspondents include: Monroe Leigh, Geoffrey C. Hazard, Jr., Abraham D. Sofaer, Memorandum for Restatement File, Richard L. Fischer, Frank P. Jones, Jr., Jennifer L. Hall, John Norton Moore
  - State Department - Permanent Court of Arbitration
    - News, 1946, 1970, 1978 (Box-folder 38 - 8)
      Contains highlights, underlines, markers, newspaper photocopies, newspaper clippings, journal excerpts, articles
    - Official Documents re: precedence, formation, functioning, 1961 - 1978 (Box-folder 38 - 9)
      Contains handwritten notations, underlines, excerpts from the American Journal of International Law re: The Permanent Court of Arbitration for 1961, 1963, 1969, "Nomination of Thomas J. Meskill" Report from the Committee on the Judiciary United States Senate together with Individual News, 1975, pamphlet: "Standing Committee on the Federal Judiciary: What it is and How it Works" American Bar Association, 1977, UN General Assembly Security Council A/33/223 S/12830 19 October 1978: Curricula vitae of candidates nominated by national groups Note by the Secretary General, text of EO 12059, 11 May 1978,
    - Rapport du Conseil Administratif de la Cour Permanente D'Arbitrage, 1976 - 1979 (Box-folder 38 - 10)
      Contains 4 reports with Monroe Leigh signature, in French language, also includes UN Gen. Assembly Security Council A/33/223/Rev. 1, 25 October 1978: Curricula vitae of candidates nominated by national groups - Note by Secretary General
    - Personal File, 1978 - 1980 (Box-folder 38 - 11)
      Contains correspondence, envelopes, memos, note cards, looseleaf notes, notations, table of U. S. members since 1938, Election of Judges to the International Court of Justice, 1981 - Sri Lanka's Candidate - Mr. H. W. Jayewardene, Correspondents include: Monroe Leigh, Cyrus Vance, Austin Pulle, Jorge A. Aja Espil, G. W. Haight, H. W. Jayewardene, Marshall Mays, Robert B. von Mehren, Roberts B. Owen, Willis L. M. Reese, Ernest A. Gross, Cecil J. Olmstead, Francis T. P. Plimpton, William W. Scranton, stephen Schwebel, Hardy C. Dillard, Timothy B. Atekson, Marco C. E. J. Bronckers, Abram Chayes, William W. Bishop, Jr., Edison W. Dick, Richard C. Allison, Philip C. Jessup, Lyon L. Brinsmade
    - Docs & Correspondence, 1977 - March 1978 (Box-folder 38 - 12)
      Contains signatures, memos, edits, notations, highlights, articles, looseleaf notes, newsletters, resumes, Correspondents include: Monroe Leigh, Herbert Brownwell, William W. Bishop, Jr., Carlyle E. Maw, Cecil J. Olmstead, Herbert W. Briggs, John R. Stevenson, Seymour Rubin, Warren E. Burger, Walter Sterling Surrey, Adrian W. De Wind, John N. Hazard, Robert Coulson, Eugene F. Scoles, Henry T. King, Jr., Austin Pulle, Richard (Dick) R. Baxter, Herbt J. Hansell, Cyrus R. Vance, Stephen M. Schwebel, Hardy C. Dillard, Erik Suy, Vanden Huevel, Millard H. Ruud, Norris Darrell, Howared M. Holtzmann, Kurt Waldheim
    - Docs & Correspondence, April - June 1978 (Box-folder 39 - 1)
      Contains memos, handwritten notes, eidts, looseleaf notes, articles, signatures, highlights, background information, reports, Correspondents include: Monroe Leigh, Carlyle E. Maw, Stephen M. Schwebel, William D. Rogers, Herbert Brownell, William W. Bishop, Jr., Herbert J. Hensell, Warren E. Burger, Cyrus Vance, Henry T. King, Jr., John Nolan, Alan Cranston, Joseph J. Sisco, Carole Smith, Millard H. Ruud, James O. Eastland, John R. Stevenson, E. Donald Shapiro, Don Wallace, Jr., Daniel P. Moynihan, Philip C. Jessup, Robert Coulson, Robert L. Trescher, W. M. Reisman, Hugo B. Margain, Eugene V. Rostow, Thomas M. Franck
    - Docs & Correspondence, July 1978 (Box-folder 39 - 2)
      Contains memos, handwritten notes, edits, underlines, table of US memebers since 1938, articles, Correspondents include: Monroe Leigh, Herbert J. Hansell, Kurt Waldheim, Cyrus Vance, Joseph S. Lord, III, Herbert Brownell, William W. Bishop, Jr., Alan M. Dershowitz, Richard (Dick) R. Baxter, Frank J. McGarr, Robert A. Sprecher, Albert Branson Maris, Stephen G. Breyer, Damon J. Keith, Walter J. Cummings, Maurice Copithorne, Carlyle E. Maw, Leonard C. Meeker, Timothy B. Atkeson, Henry T. King, Warren E. Burger, William D. Rogers
    - Letter to Vance materials, July 1978 (Box-folder 39 - 3)
      Contains various drafts of letters re: International Court of Justice and Cyrus R. Vance, supporting materials, notations, highlights, memos, table of U.S. members since 1946, table fo U.S. members since 1938, routing slips, and correspondence indicating that ML had requested materials be returned and then the returned copies are included, articles, Correspondents include: Monroe Leigh, Cyrus R. Vance, Henry T. King, Jr., Millard H. Ruud, Gerald Asken,
    - Anderson Telecast of 7/28/78 28 July 1978 (Box-folder 39 - 4)
      Contains transcripts, scripts, underlines, edits, comments, signatures, Who's Who in America excerpted photocopies, Who's Who in the World excerpted photocopies, Directory of American Scholars excerpted photocopies, The International Who's Who excerpted photocopies, newspaper clippings, Correspondents include: Monroe Leigh, Pegi McLaughlin, Arthur J. Goldberg
    - Letter to Kurt Waldeim, July 1978 (Box-folder 39 - 5)
      Materials for correspondence with Kurt Waldeim, Secretary General of the United Nations, from William W. Bishop, Jr., Herbert Brownell, Herbert J. Hansell, Monroe Leigh
    - Press Release, 1 August 1978 (Box-folder 39 - 6)
    - Docs & Correspondence, Aug - Sept. 1978 (Box-folder 39 - 7)
      Contains memos, signatures, photocopies of telegrams, handwritten letters, transcripts of speeches, resumes, draft press release, Correspondents include: Monroe Leigh, Richard (Dick) R. Baxter, Herbert J. Hansell, Alan J. Kreczko, Leonard v. B. Sutton, Seymour J. Rubin, Adrian W. DeWind, John Scott, Hardy Dillard, John R. Stevenson, Stephen M. Schwebel, Warren E. Burger, John N Hazard, Robert Coulson, Henry T. King, Millard H. Ruud, William W. Bishop, Jr., Arthur J. Goldberg,
    - Docs & Correspondence, Oct 1978 - July 1980 (Box-folder 39 - 8)
      Contains handwritten notations, photocopies, agendas, correspondents include: Monroe Leigh, Robert H. Mundheim, Austin Pulle, J. Wallace Hopkins, Jr., Michael Bradfield, Carlyle E. Maw, Stephen M. Schwebel, Max Frankel, Richard R. Baxter, Cyrus Vance, Cecil J. Olmstead, Herbert J. Hansell
    - Docs & Correspondence, Sept. 1980 - Dec. 1980 (Box-folder 39 - 9)
      Contains index, memos, looseleaf notes, envelopes, markup, edits, mailing lists, messenger requests, Correspondents include: Monroe Leigh, J. Varekamp, Roberts B. Owen, Keith Highet, William W. Bishop, Jr., Edmund S. Muskie, Lyon L. Brinsmade, Hardy Dillard, Eric Stein, Richard L. McCall, John J. McCloy, Michael Reisman, R. Ammi Cutter, Daniel J. Boorstin, James E. O'Brien, Stephen M. Schwebel, Leonard C. Meeker, W. Graham Claytor, Jr., Seymour J. Rubin, Abdulloh El-Erain, Erik Suy, Abram Chayes, George J. Alexander, Richard H. Ullman, Michael I. Sovern, Adrian S. Fisher, Warren E. Burger, Herbert W. Briggs, Al Freeman, Oscar M. Ruebhausen, Robert M. von Mehren, Albert M. Sacks, Robert Coulson, Merrell E. Clark, Jr., Austin Pulle, Herb Hansell
    - Performance Review, 1980 - 1981 (Box-folder 39 - 10)
      Contains handwritten comments, notes, signature, underlines, Foreign Affairs Manual Circular, Vol. 3 - Personnel (1980 and 1981), Presidentail Ranks - Score Sheet, Panel B, Correspondents include: Monroe Leigh, Joan M. Clark, John H. Rouse,
    - Statute, 1907 Constitution, 1899 Constitution, 1978 [1907], [1899], 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 1)
      Contains pencil markup, "Preliminary Summary of Support by Groups Consulted, for U. S. nominee to ICJ"
    - Court Composition: Foreign Candidates for Nomination, 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 2)
      Names include: Roberto Ago (Italy), Jiminez De Arechaga (Uruguay), Abdullah El-Erian (Egypt), Antonio Gomez Robledo (Mexico), L. Ignacio-Pinto (Benin), H. W. Jayewaredene (Sri Lanka), Eero J. Manner (Finland), Jose Sette Camara (Brazil)
    - Court Composition: Ago, Roberto, 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 3)
      b. May 26, 1907 according to original file container, Contains correspondence (2 letters) regarding Robert Ago of Italy between John R. Stevenson, Herbert W. Briggs, Don Wallace, Jr., Millard H. Rudd, includes highlights and notations
    - Court Composition: De Arechaga, Jiminez, 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 4)
      Contains correspondence (2 letters) regarding Jiminez De Arechaga (Uruguary) between Monroe Leigh, William D. Rogers, John R. Stevenson, Herbert W. Briggs
    - Court Composition: El-Erian, Abdullah, 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 5)
      b. March 21, 1920 according to original file container, Contains resume, correspondence (1 letter) regarding Abdullah El-Erian between Monroe Leigh, Philip C. Jessup
    - Court Composition: Gomez Robledo, Antonio, 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 6)
      b. November 17, 1908 according to original file container, Contains curriculum vitae, highlights, correspondence (3 letters) regarding Antonio Gomez Robledo (Mexico) between Hugo B. Margain, Monroe Leigh, the Department of State, John R. Stevenson, Herbert W. Briggs
    - Court Composition: Jayewaredene, H. W., 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 7)
      b. 1916 according to original file container, Contains resume, highlights, pencil mark-up, correspondence regarding H. W. Jayewaredene (Sri Lanka) between Cyrus R. Vance, A. C. S. Hameed, the Department of State, the Permanent Mission of Sri Lanka to the U.N.
    - Court Composition: Ignacio-Pinto, Louis, 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 8)
      b. June 21, 1903 according to original file container, Contains handwritten memo, correspondence (1 letter) regarding Louis Ignacio-Pinto (Benin) between Monroe Leigh, William D. Rogers
    - Court Composition: Manner, Eero J., 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 9)
      b. July 16, 1913 according to original file container, Contains curriculum vitae, correspondence (2 letters) regarding Eero J. Manner (Finland) between John R. Stevenson, Herbert W. Briggs, the Department of State, the Embassy of Finland
    - Court Composition: Sette Camara, Jose, 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 10)
      b. April 14, 1920 according to original file container, Contains highlights, resume, Correspondence (3 letters) regarding Jose Sette Camara (Brazil) between the Department of State, the Permanent Mission of Brazil to the U. N., Vanden Huevel, John R. Stevenson, Herbert W. Briggs
    - Court Composition: List of United States Candidates, 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 11)
      Names include: Richard R. Baxter, Nathan R. Berke, Hardy C. Dillard, Walter Ely, Arthur J. Goldberg, Leo Gross, Louis Henkin, Myres S. McDougal, Robert B. McKay, Carlyle E. Maw, Russell D. Niles, Covey T. Oliber, Oscar Schachter, Bernard G. Segal, Louis B. Sohn, William B. Spong, Jr., John R. Stevenson
    - Court Composition: The Chief Justice of the United States, 27 June 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 12)
      Contains highlights, letter from Warren E. Burger to Monroe Leigh
    - Court Composition: American Bar Association Section of International Law, 21 June 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 13)
      Contains highlights, letter from Henry T. King, Jr., to Monroe Leigh
    - Court Composition: American Society of International Law, 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 14)
      Contains highlights, press release and letter (dated 29 June 1978) from William D. Rogers to Monroe Leigh
    - Court Composition: American Branch International Law Association, 30 June 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 15)
      Contains highlights, letter from Carlyle E. Maw to Monroe Leigh
    - Court Composition: Association of American Law Schools, 9 June 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 16)
      Contains highlights, letter from Millard H. Ruud to Monroe Leigh
    - Court Composition: Association of the Bar of the City of New York, 1 May 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 17)
      Contains highlights, personal note, letter from Herbert Brownell to Monroe Leigh
    - Court Composition: American Arbitration Association, 9 May 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 18)
      Contains highlights, letter from Robert Coulson to Monroe Leigh
    - Court Composition: Baxter, Richard R., 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 19)
      b. February 14, 1921 according to original file container, contains highlights, correspondence regarding Richard R. Baxter, background information, bibliographies, letters of support, resume, Correspondents include: Monroe Leigh, Herbert J. Hansell, Millard H. Ruud, Don Wallace, Jr., Carlyle E. Maw, William D. Rogers, Robert Coulson, Thomas M. Franck, Henry T. King, Jr.,
    - Court Composition: Berke, Nathan R., 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 20)
      Contains correspondence (2 letters) regarding Nathan R. Berke between Monroe Leigh, Alan Cranston, Douglas J. Bennet, Jr., President Jimmy Carter
    - Court Composition: Dillard, Hardy C., 27 June 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 21)
      Contains highlights, letter regarding Hardy C. Dillard between Monroe Leigh and Warren E. Burger
    - Court Composition: Ely, Walter, 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 22)
      Contains highlights, correspondence (2 letters) regarding Walter Ely between Herbert Brownell, Robert L. Trescher, Shirley M. Hufstedler
    - Court Composition: Goldberg, Arthur J., 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 23)
      b. August 8, 1908 according to original file container, contains highlights, underlines, resume, biographical information, correspondence regarding Arthur J. Goldberg, Correspondents include: Herbert J. Hansell, Fred J. Cassibry, Alfonso J. Zirpoli, Julius J. Hoffman, James B. Parsons, Walter E. Craig, Joseph S. Lord, III, Alan M. Dershowitz, Frank J. McGarr, Robert A. Sprecher, Albert Branson Maris, Stephen G. Breyer, William J. Campbell, Hubert H. Humphrey, Howard H. Baker, Frank Church, President Jimmy Carter, Damon J. Keith, Walter J. Cummings, Leonard C. Meeker, Joseph J. Sisco
    - Court Composition: Gross, Leo, 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 24)
      b. April 6, 1903 according to original file container, contains highlights, resume, biographical information, correspondence regarding Leo Gross, Correspondents include: Millard H. Ruud, Edward Gordon, Daniel P. Moynihan, Monroe Leigh
    - Court Composition: Henkin, Louis, 30 June 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 25)
      Contains highlights, letter regarding Louis Henkin between Leonard C. Meeker and Monroe Leigh
    - Court Composition: Maw, Carlyle, 1 May 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 26)
      Contains highlights, letter regarding Carlyle E. Maw between Herbert Brownwell and Monroe Leigh
    - Court Composition: McDougal, Myres S., 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 27)
      b. November 23. 1906 according to original file container, contains highlights, biographical and bibliographical information, correspondence regarding Myres S. McDougal, Correspondents include: Elliott Goldstein, Herbert J. Hansell, President Jimmy Carter, John C. Stennis, James O. Eastland, Monroe Leigh, W. M. Reisman, Eugene V. Rostow, William W. Bishop, Jr., E. Donald Shapiro, Millard H. Ruud, Edward Gordon, Emerson G. Spies, Frank Moore,
    - Court Composition: McKay, Robert B., 1 May 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 28)
      Contains highlights, letter regarding Robert B. McKay between Monroe Leigh and Herbert Brownwell
    - Court Composition: Niles, Russell D., 27 June 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 29)
      Contains highlights, letter regarding Russell D. Niles between Monroe Leigh and Warren E. Burger
    - Court Composition: Oliver, Covey T., 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 30)
      b. April 21, 1913 according to original file container, contains highlights, AALS Directory of Law Teachers excerpt, Who's Who in America exceprt, letter dated 9 June 1978 regaring Covey T. Oliver between Monroe Leigh and Millard H. Ruud
    - Court Composition: Schachter, Oscar, 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 31)
      Contains highlights, correspondence (2 letters) regarding Oscar Schachter between John R. Stevenson, Herbert W. Briggs, Millard H. Ruud, Edward Gordon
    - Court Composition: Segal, Bernard G., 27 June 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 32)
      Contains highlights, letter regarding Bernard G. Segal between Monroe Leigh and Warren E. Burger
    - Court Composition: Sohn, Louis B., 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 33)
      b. March 1, 1974 according to original file container, contains highlights, biographical and bibliographical information, correspondence regaridng Louis B. Sohn, Correspondents include: Herbt J. Hansell, Henry T. King, Jr., Monroe Leigh, Robert Coulson
    - Court Composition: Spong, William B., Jr., 27 June 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 34)
      Contains highlights, letter regarding William B. Spong, Jr. between Monroe Leigh and Warren E. Burger
    - Court Composition: Stevenson, John R., 1 May 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 35)
      Contains highlights, letter regarding John R. Stevenson between Monroe Leigh and Herbt Brownwell
    - Court Composition: Memorandum and Correspondence, June - July 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 36)
      Contains supporting documents, underlines, Correspondents include: Monroe Leigh, Austin Pulle, Arthur J. Goldberg, William W. Bishop, Jr.
    - Court Composition: Memorandum from Austin Pulle re: American Members of the PCA, 18 July 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 37)
      Contains underlines, handwritten notations, PCA reports starting in 1900
    - Court Composition: Memorandum to Austin Pulle, 15 March 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 38)
      Contains underlines, handwritten notations, articles about the PCA
    - Court Composition: Booklet w/overview of PCA and nominations, 1978 (Box-folder 40 - 39)
      Index: Statute of the International Court of Justice, Present Members of the International Court of Justice, Procedure for Election of Judges, American Candidates, Foreign Candidates (Ambassador El-Erian (Egypt), Mr. Razafindralambro (Madagascar), Ambassador Sette Camara (Brazil), Dr. Gomez Robledo (Mexico), Professor Robert Ago (Italy), Judge Manner (Finland), Mr. Jayawardene (Sri Lanka)), Past Nominations by the US National Group
  - Red Cross
    - National Red Cross Societies, 1952 and 18 Oct 1957 (Box-folder 41 - 1)
      Contains "Guide for National Red Cross Societies on their Role as Auxiliaries of the Army Medical and Civil Defence Services" - Geneva, 1952 and Memorandum re: Summary of Participation and Probable Voting Position of Governments and National Red Cross Societies as of October 18, 1957
    - XIXth International Conference of the Red Cross - Correspondence / Background Materials, June - Nov 1957 (Box-folder 41 - 2)
      Contains notations, signatures, Correspondents include: U. S. Delegation, Orlando Pedragosa Nadal (Delegate of Uruguay), Dr. Muhlenhover (Delgate of Germany, Amrit Kaur (Chairman, XIXth International Red Cross Conference), General Gruenther, James T. Nicholson, Mr. Boissier, Ellsworth Bunker, Robert McClintock (Delegate of USA), George M. Elsey, John Foster Dulles
    - XIXth International Conference of the Red Cross - Programs and Schedules, Oct - Nov 1957 (Box-folder 41 - 3)
      Contains notations, schedules for each day of the Conference (28 Oct - 7 Nov), list of delegates, governing rules
    - XIXth International Conference of the Red Cross - Drafts / Resolutions, Oct - Nov 1957 (Box-folder 41 - 4)
      Contians notations, edits, markup, copies of various drafts and resolutions proposed by different countries in attendance at the Conference
  - International Water Rights
    - Principles of Law Governing the Uses of International Rivers and Lakes: Resolution adopted by the Inter-American Bar Associaiton at its Tenth Conference Held in November, 1957, at Buenos Aires, Argentina, together with Papers Submitted to the Association. Washington, DC. April, 1958 (Box-folder 41 -)
      Removed to collections in library because there were no markings
    - Principles of Law and Recommendations on the Uses of International Rivers: Statement of Principles of Law and Recommendations with a Commentary and Supporting Authorities Submitted to the International Committee of the International Law Association by the Committee on the Uses of Waters of International Rivers of the American Branch. Washington, DC. May, 1958 (Box-folder 41 -)
      Removed because all materials can be found online or in the library [Law Basement - Oceans 13.6.I6146P
    - "Pakistan: The Struggle for Irrigation Water - and Existence" pamphlet, 1 November 1953 (Box-folder 41 - 5)
      Issued by the Embassy of Pakistan, Washington, D.C.
    - "Apportionment in Indus Basin of Waters Common to Pakistan and India": For Official Use Only, Confidential, n.d. (Box-folder 41 - 6)
      Contains inked edits and markings in the footnotes, Leigh signature
    - Memorandum re: [Legal]Arguments to Pakistan in Event Issue Raised as to Legality of Purported Accession by Kashmir to India," 18 Nov 1949 (Box-folder 41 - 7)
      Contains Leigh signature, minor edits and markup
    - Annex G: Selected Treaties, Conventions, and Agreements, [1949] (Box-folder 41 - 8)
      Contains edits, markup, notations
    - Annex G deletions: Selected Treaties, Conventions, and Agreements removed from Annex G, July 1949 (Box-folder 41 - 9)
      Contains edits, markup, notations, attached notes
    - U.S. & Canada and U.S. & Great Britain precedents and research, 1949 [1909] (Box-folder 41 - 10)
      Contains markup, notations, looseleaf notes, briefs
    - Memorandum for File 8619: Canadian-American Approach to Solution of Water Rights Controversy, 1949 (Box-folder 42 - 1)
      Contains markup, notations
    - Memorandum re: Murray River Research, Feb - March, 1949 [1902] (Box-folder 42 - 2)
      Contains 1 document with two attachments, including 1 - The Development of the Murray River and 2 - Synopsis of Report of the Inter-State Royal Commission on the River Murray (1902)